Guide to the Laird Evans Collection, 1970-2014 IBT0078
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Laird Evans Collection
1959-2016
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT0078
5.5 Linear Feet Printed matter, contracts, photos, truck models - 4 cartons
This collection contains materials collected by Laird Evans over the course of his career as a Teamster.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by subject.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Laird Evans, 2016 (2016.055)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains materials collected by Laird Evans. Materials include IBT publications, materials from IBT Local 568, materials relating to Laird Evan's book "And Justice For All...Even Teamsters."
Biographical / Historical
Laird Evans worked as a Business Agent and Secretary/Treasurer for Local 568 in Shreveport, Louisiana for almost 30 years. He is the author of "And Justice For All...Even Teamsters!"
General
- Texas Conference of Teamsters Photo Album, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Teamsters Joint Council 80 Photo Album, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Teamsters Joint Council 80 Photo Album, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Laird Evans Information, 1977-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Grievance Guide 4th Edition, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Local 568 Labor Agreements, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Master Tank Line Agreements Southern Conference of Teamsters, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Master Rail-Truck Freight Agreements Southwest Area, 1970-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Federal Mediation Conciliation Services Arbitration between Local 988 and Jack Cooper Transportation Company, inc, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Agreement between IBT local 968 and Hertz Corporation, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Welcome to the Teamsters Booklet, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Central Trades and Labor Council of Shreveport and Vicinity Labor Day Celebration event pamphlet, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Teamsters Joint Council No. 83 of Virginia Welfare Funds Booklets, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Greyhound Fair Labor Contract Strike Photograph, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Joseph 'Tiny' Lamartine Local 568 Poster Child, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Double Cross of Jimmy Hoffa, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- What is the Teamsters Union? Booklet, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Central States, Southwest and Southeast Areas Roadguide to your Pension Plan Booklet (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Misc. Photographs, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Fighting for Good Jobs at UPS: A Steward's Guide to Enforcing the National Agreement, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Federal Motor Carrier Safety Regulations Book, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Local 568 History Book Chapter Draft, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Local 568 Affiliation Charter Scanned Photograph, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Miller Transporter Inc Driver's Manual, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- NLRB Rules and Regulations and Procedure Labor Relations Act Booklet, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Southern Region of Teamsters Summary Plan Descriptions, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Labor and the Bible Booklet, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Carolina Freight Routing Guide, ND (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Churchill Truck Lines, Inc Mileage Chart, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- "Fight for Me" Jimmy R. Hoffa Booklet, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- "In Memoriam" Blank Card and Envelope (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Misc. Stickers and Postcards (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Various Newspaper Clippings and Cartoons, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- "The State of the Union" Jackie Presser Forbes Article, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Hoffa's Corner "Will Fishy Funds Sink Carey" Trade Union Courier Article, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- The International Teamster Magazine, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Union Industries and Trade Service Show Save the Date, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- American Labor Beacon Magazine, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Teamsters on Parade "79" News Magazine, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Ritual of IBT booklet, ND (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Absentee Ballot Request Book, 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Southern Multi-State Grievance Committee Decisions, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- IBT Focus on Members Booklet, ND (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Welcome to the Teamsters Booklet, ND (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Why Unions are Good for your Family Booklet, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Labor Agreement between Foremost Dairies, Inc and IBT Local 568, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Agreement Between Chemical Express Carriers, Inc and Various Locals, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- The Rats are Chewing Away at our Union Volume 2, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Grievance Guide Sixth Edition, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Solidarity Forever and a Happy New Year Card (Box 3, Folder 9)
- HR. 5 and S. 55 Senate Support Postcards, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Labor in the Schools Booklet, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Arbitration Between Local 568 and ITT Continental Baking Company, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- The International Teamster Magazine, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Teamsters Magazine Union Busting Groups Excerpt, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Teamster Magazine, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Teamsters for Liberty Correspondence, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Employee Free Choice Act Flyer, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Ryder Truck Drivers Safe Driving Certificate, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Driver's Pocket Guide to Hazardous Materials, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Federal Motor Carrier Safety Regulations Pocket Book, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- The VOICE of Local 391 Newspaper, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Texas Teamsters Newsletter, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Teamsters Newspaper Clippings, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Misc. Photographs, ND (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Laird Evans Information Collection, 1977-2001 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Local 568 Plaque, ND (Box 6, Object 1)
- Local 568 Muscular Dystrophy Association Plaque, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Local 568 Muscular Dystrophy Association Plaque, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Laid Evans Local 568 Food Bank of the Arklatex, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Appreciative Award Presented to Laird Evans from Local 568, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Local 568 Muscular Dystrophy Association Plaque, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Local 568 Telethon Plaque, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Local 568 Telethon Plaque, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Local 568 Telethon Plaque, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Local 568 Telethon Plaque, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Executive Board Minutes Book, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Executive Board Minutes Book, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- General Meeting Minutes Book, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Executive Board Minutes Book, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- General Meeting Minutes Book, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Election Palmcard - Re-Elect Incumbents and Note, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- What is the Teamsters Union? Booklet, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1978-1995 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Labor Agreement Between Miller Transportations, Inc and Southern Conference of Teamsters, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- The State of the Union by Allan Dodds Frank, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Loose News Clippings, 1983-2011 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- The International Teamster Magazine, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- US News Magazine, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- 24th Convention Resolutions Committee Badge, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Local 568 Application- Kint LaMartine, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- James P. Hoffa Campaign and 1996 Election Materials, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Retirement Banquet, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- By, America by Lance Biglin, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Employee Free Choice Act Information, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- James R. Hoffa Memorial Scholarship Fund Blank Application, 2010-2011 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Political Emails, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Editorial to Shreveport Times about the Important of Unions, ND (Box 8, Folder 22)
- MDA Charity News Clippings and Photographs (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Welcome to the Teamsters Booklet, ND (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Miscellaneous Printed Matter, ND (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Photographs, ND (Box 8, Folder 26)
- "Do You Know What Foremen and Supervisors Can Not Do" Flyer (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Southern Conference of Teamsters Authorization Cards, ND (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Blank Local 568 Warning Letters, ND (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Local 568 Official Ballot, 1980; IBT0078 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Elect Morgan '81 Patch, 1981; IBT0078 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- The International Teamster, 1987-1989; IBT0078 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Local 568 Perini Referrals, 1992; IBT0078 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- The Washington Times Teamsters Perks Article, 1995; IBT0078 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- C.E. Byrd High School Alumni Newsletter, 2013; IBT0078 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- AFL-CIO Shreveport Labor Day Program, 2016; IBT0078 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- "And Justice for All...Even Teamsters" Book Talk Information, Undated; IBT0078 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Files, Undated; IBT0078 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Local 745 Clipboard and Folder, Undated; IBT0078 (Box 9, Loose-material 10)
- Jimmy Hoffa Jr. Addressing Teamsters Local 710 Cassette Tape, Undated; IBT0078 (Box 9, Loose-material 11)
- Reagan Bush '80 Pin, 1980; IBT0078 (Box 9, Loose-material 12)
- Shut Overnite Management Down Pin, 1999; IBT0078 (Box 9, Loose-material 13)
- Laird Evans Postcard "And Justice For All", Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- UPS "Teams" Pamplet, ND; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Response to Stand Records Service President, 1975; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Grievance Correspondence, 1979; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- 1977 Election Materials, 1976-1977; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- International Convention Delegate Ribbons, 2001; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- IBT Second Conference Call Tape/Teamsters Local #5 6 Spots @ 60 Seconds Tape, 1997; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Various Teamster/BTE Election Badges and Pins, 1980-2000; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Various Teamster/BTE Election Badges and Pins, 1986; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Truck Models, Undated; 1.5 Cubic Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of truck models collected by Laird Evans. These trucks represent some of the companies the Teamsters have worked with. The trucks are in varying conditions.
  Arrangement
  Models in this series are arranged by box. There is no particular order to the models in the boxes.
  - Truck Models, Undated (Box 10, Box Box 10)
    This box contains truck models collected by Laird Evans. Models in this box consist of: Churchill Truck Lines, inc trailer (2 trailers), Preston People trailer, ABF truck (2 trucks), P.I.E. trucks (3 trucks, all different versions), Roadway express, inc trucks (5 trucks, all different versions), and Consolidated Freightways trucks (4 trucks).
  - Truck Models, Undated (Box 11, Box Box 11)
    This box contains truck models collected by Laird Evans. Models in this box consist of: Ryder P.I.E. truck, Transcon trailer, GF Consolidated Freightweighters truck, McLean Trucking Company truck, Mopac Moyer Packing Company truck, ABF truck, and a large United Parcel Service truck.
  - Truck Models, Undated (Box 12, Box Box 12)
    This box contains truck models collected by Laird Evans. Models in this box consist of: Gordon Transports, Inc truck, UBC large truck without trailer, Steve D. Thompson Trucking, inc truck, Campbell Express truck, Graves ANR freight system truck, Lee Way truck, Roadway Express, inc truck, TIME-DC truck, Churchill Truck Lines, inc truck without trailer, McLean Trucking Company trucks (2 trucks), and a AG Kits, Toys, Collectibles, and Die Cast Metal Replicas car model.